drugrehabcenter.com 2010-08-01

# Privacy Policy

**G &G Holistic Addiction Treatment Cenetr, Inc. (hereinafter Holistic) has a strong commitment to respecting your concerns about privacy. We understand that you might wonder whether and how this Website collects and uses information. This statement contains numerous general and technical details about the steps we take to respect your privacy concerns. **

**  
Browsing:**  
This website does not collect any personal information from your computer when browsing this site. Unless you give us written permission to post information on our secure and private Alumni Information Form or request a reply using one of our feedback or reply forms, we will not know your name, your e-mail address, or any other information that identifies you.   
Internet Protocol (IP) Address:  
An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer every time you browse the Internet. When you request a page from our site, our server logs your current IP address. We would only use your IP address to help diagnose problems that affect the integrity of our computer systems, not for personal identification of any users. 

**Cookies**  
Holistic does not send or set cookies on your machine.

**Information Needed to Execute the Transaction You Request:**  
When we need to collect information from you, we will ask you to voluntarily supply us with the information we need. For example, if you would like to receive information about admission to Holistic, you may fill out the Inquiry Form in the Admissions section which requests information about your name, address, phone number and e-mail address plus a place to check programs you wish to receive information about and a place to write your question, plus questions about how you heard about us (for evaluation of our own marketing practices). We will use your e-mail address only to provide the information you requested, or to communicate news as you requested. If at any time you decide you do not want to receive this information, you may let us know by reply e-mail or use the form to request that we no longer contact you. Providing information to us using any of our on-line forms is voluntary and the information we collect is used only for the purpose for which the information was collected and is not shared with any other companies. 

**  
Securing the Transmission and Storage of Information:**  
When we ask you for personal data in any of our forms on-line information is transferred over a Secured Sockets Layer (SSL) line provided you are using an SSL enabled browser such as Microsoft Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator. This ensures that your information is encrypted as it travels over the Internet. This secure mode is enabled before any such information is transmitted from your computer. After information reaches Holistic it is stored on a secure server that resides behind a firewall that is designed to block access from outside the Center.

**Holistic Use of Information:**  
We treat the information that you provide to us as confidential information. It is, accordingly, subject to Holistics security procedures and strict corporate policies regarding protection and use of information. We will only disclose this information to individuals at Holistic on a need-to-know basis and person(s) authorized by you. Patient information is additionally protected under the Code of Federal Regulations, Title 42 and the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA). Holistic maintains strict compliance with each of these laws and regulations.

The laws applicable to personal information vary from country to country. The information we process and store is kept in accordance with the applicable United States legal requirements, which may not be as comprehensive as the data protection laws found in other countries, such as those in the European Union. 

**E-Mails and Opt-Out:**  
Our goal is to only send e-mails that are likely to be of interest to you. All e-mail is generated from Holistic and not from an outside third-party e-mail service provider. Holistic does not make e-mail addresses available to any partners in the Holistic Network or to any others for their use. You may at any time request not to receive e-mails from Holistic by replying to any e-mail with your request to opt-out.

**Disclosure of Information to Third Parties:**  
Holistic prohibits the sale or transfer of personal information to anyone outside the Holistic imeediate internal network.

**Links to Other Sites:**  
Other sites linked to by the Holistic website are offered for your convenience only. Holistic is not responsible for the privacy policies of those sites, or for cookies those sites might use.

**Legal Issues:**  
This is a United States website and subject to United States law. Holistic will disclose personal health information without your permission only when required by law, or in a good faith belief that such action is necessary to investigate or protect against harmful activities to Holistic patients, staff, volunteers, alumni, property (including this site) or to others or as authorized by federal medical privacy rules under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act. 

**Holistic Privacy Statement Changes:**  
In the future, we may need to change the privacy statement for www.drugrehabcenter.com. All changes will be made here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Any changes made in the future will only apply to information collected after any new policy is established. 

**How to Contact Us:**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement or privacy concerns, please send an e-mail to:  
privacyofficer@drugrehabcenter.com 

(Jerry this goes into the policy manual under a separate heading and with your signature as CTO)  
NOTICE OF PRIVACY PRACTICES  
As of April 1, 2006  
THIS NOTICE DESCRIBES HOW MEDICAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU MAY BE USED AND DISCLOSED AND HOW YOU CAN GET ACCESS TO THIS INFORMATION. PLEASE REVIEW THIS NOTICE CAREFULLY.  
Your health record contains personal information about you and your health. State and federal law protects the confidentiality of this information. "Protected health information" is information about you, including demographic information, that may identify you and that relates to your past, present or future physical or mental health or condition and related health care services. The confidentiality of alcohol and drug abuse patient records is specifically protected by Federal law and regulations. Holistic is required to comply with these additional restrictions. This includes a prohibition, with very few exceptions, on informing anyone outside the program that you attend the program or disclosing any information that identifies you as an alcohol or drug abuser. The violation of Federal laws or regulations by this program is a crime. If you suspect a violation you may file a report to the appropriate authorities in accordance with Federal regulations.   
How We May Use and Disclose Health Information About You  
• For Treatment. We may use medical and clinical information about you to provide you with treatment or services.  
• For Payment. With your authorization, we may use and disclose medical information about you so that we can receive payment for the treatment services provided to you.   
• For Health Care Operations. We may use and disclose your protected health information ("PHI") for certain purposes in connection with the operation of our program.  
• Without Authorization. Applicable law also permits us to disclose information about you without your authorization in a limited number of other situations, such as with a court order. These situations are explained on the following pages.  
• With Authorization. We must obtain written authorization from you for other uses and disclosures of your PHI.   
Your Rights Regarding Your PHI.  
You have the following rights regarding PHI we maintain about you:   
• Right of Access to Inspect and Copy. You have the right, which may be restricted in certain circumstances, to inspect and copy PHI that may be used to make decisions about your care. We may charge a reasonable, cost-based fee for copies.  
• Right to Amend. If you feel that the PHI we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, you may ask us to amend the information although we are not required to agree to the amendment.   
• Right to an Accounting of Disclosures. You have the right to request an accounting of the disclosures that we make of your PHI. There are exceptions that do not require accounting for, including disclosures made for the purposes of treatment, payment, health care operations or pursuant to an authorization.  
• Right to Request Restrictions. You have the right to request a restriction or limitation on the use or of your PHI for treatment, payment, or health care operations. We are not required to agree to your request.  
• Right to Request Confidential Communication. You have the right to request that we communicate with you about medical matters in a certain way or at a certain location.  
• Right to a Copy of this Notice. You have the right to a copy of this notice.  
• Complaints. You have the right to file a complaint in writing to us or to the Secretary of Health and Human Services if you believe we have violated your privacy rights. We will not retaliate against you for filing a complaint.  
If you have any questions about this Notice of Privacy Practices, Please contact our Privacy Officer:  
Rick Murphy  
rick@drugrehabcenter.com  

**G &G Holistic Addiction Treatment Cenetr, Inc. (hereinafter Holistic) has a strong commitment to respecting your concerns about privacy. We understand that you might wonder whether and how this Website collects and uses information. This statement contains numerous general and technical details about the steps we take to respect your privacy concerns. **

**  
Browsing:**  
This website does not collect any personal information from your computer when browsing this site. Unless you give us written permission to post information on our secure and private Alumni Information Form or request a reply using one of our feedback or reply forms, we will not know your name, your e-mail address, or any other information that identifies you.   
Internet Protocol (IP) Address:  
An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer every time you browse the Internet. When you request a page from our site, our server logs your current IP address. We would only use your IP address to help diagnose problems that affect the integrity of our computer systems, not for personal identification of any users. 

**Cookies**  
Holistic does not send or set cookies on your machine.

**Information Needed to Execute the Transaction You Request:**  
When we need to collect information from you, we will ask you to voluntarily supply us with the information we need. For example, if you would like to receive information about admission to Holistic, you may fill out the Inquiry Form in the Admissions section which requests information about your name, address, phone number and e-mail address plus a place to check programs you wish to receive information about and a place to write your question, plus questions about how you heard about us (for evaluation of our own marketing practices). We will use your e-mail address only to provide the information you requested, or to communicate news as you requested. If at any time you decide you do not want to receive this information, you may let us know by reply e-mail or use the form to request that we no longer contact you. Providing information to us using any of our on-line forms is voluntary and the information we collect is used only for the purpose for which the information was collected and is not shared with any other companies. 

**  
Securing the Transmission and Storage of Information:**  
When we ask you for personal data in any of our forms on-line information is transferred over a Secured Sockets Layer (SSL) line provided you are using an SSL enabled browser such as Microsoft Internet Explorer or Netscape Navigator. This ensures that your information is encrypted as it travels over the Internet. This secure mode is enabled before any such information is transmitted from your computer. After information reaches Holistic it is stored on a secure server that resides behind a firewall that is designed to block access from outside the Center.

**Holistic Use of Information:**  
We treat the information that you provide to us as confidential information. It is, accordingly, subject to Holistics security procedures and strict corporate policies regarding protection and use of information. We will only disclose this information to individuals at Holistic on a need-to-know basis and person(s) authorized by you. Patient information is additionally protected under the Code of Federal Regulations, Title 42 and the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA). Holistic maintains strict compliance with each of these laws and regulations.

The laws applicable to personal information vary from country to country. The information we process and store is kept in accordance with the applicable United States legal requirements, which may not be as comprehensive as the data protection laws found in other countries, such as those in the European Union. 

**E-Mails and Opt-Out:**  
Our goal is to only send e-mails that are likely to be of interest to you. All e-mail is generated from Holistic and not from an outside third-party e-mail service provider. Holistic does not make e-mail addresses available to any partners in the Holistic Network or to any others for their use. You may at any time request not to receive e-mails from Holistic by replying to any e-mail with your request to opt-out.

**Disclosure of Information to Third Parties:**  
Holistic prohibits the sale or transfer of personal information to anyone outside the Holistic imeediate internal network.

**Links to Other Sites:**  
Other sites linked to by the Holistic website are offered for your convenience only. Holistic is not responsible for the privacy policies of those sites, or for cookies those sites might use.

**Legal Issues:**  
This is a United States website and subject to United States law. Holistic will disclose personal health information without your permission only when required by law, or in a good faith belief that such action is necessary to investigate or protect against harmful activities to Holistic patients, staff, volunteers, alumni, property (including this site) or to others or as authorized by federal medical privacy rules under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act. 

**Holistic Privacy Statement Changes:**  
In the future, we may need to change the privacy statement for www.drugrehabcenter.com. All changes will be made here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Any changes made in the future will only apply to information collected after any new policy is established. 

**How to Contact Us:**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement or privacy concerns, please send an e-mail to:  
privacyofficer@drugrehabcenter.com 

(Jerry this goes into the policy manual under a separate heading and with your signature as CTO)  
NOTICE OF PRIVACY PRACTICES  
As of April 1, 2006  
THIS NOTICE DESCRIBES HOW MEDICAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU MAY BE USED AND DISCLOSED AND HOW YOU CAN GET ACCESS TO THIS INFORMATION. PLEASE REVIEW THIS NOTICE CAREFULLY.  
Your health record contains personal information about you and your health. State and federal law protects the confidentiality of this information. "Protected health information" is information about you, including demographic information, that may identify you and that relates to your past, present or future physical or mental health or condition and related health care services. The confidentiality of alcohol and drug abuse patient records is specifically protected by Federal law and regulations. Holistic is required to comply with these additional restrictions. This includes a prohibition, with very few exceptions, on informing anyone outside the program that you attend the program or disclosing any information that identifies you as an alcohol or drug abuser. The violation of Federal laws or regulations by this program is a crime. If you suspect a violation you may file a report to the appropriate authorities in accordance with Federal regulations.   
How We May Use and Disclose Health Information About You  
• For Treatment. We may use medical and clinical information about you to provide you with treatment or services.  
• For Payment. With your authorization, we may use and disclose medical information about you so that we can receive payment for the treatment services provided to you.   
• For Health Care Operations. We may use and disclose your protected health information ("PHI") for certain purposes in connection with the operation of our program.  
• Without Authorization. Applicable law also permits us to disclose information about you without your authorization in a limited number of other situations, such as with a court order. These situations are explained on the following pages.  
• With Authorization. We must obtain written authorization from you for other uses and disclosures of your PHI.   
Your Rights Regarding Your PHI.  
You have the following rights regarding PHI we maintain about you:   
• Right of Access to Inspect and Copy. You have the right, which may be restricted in certain circumstances, to inspect and copy PHI that may be used to make decisions about your care. We may charge a reasonable, cost-based fee for copies.  
• Right to Amend. If you feel that the PHI we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, you may ask us to amend the information although we are not required to agree to the amendment.   
• Right to an Accounting of Disclosures. You have the right to request an accounting of the disclosures that we make of your PHI. There are exceptions that do not require accounting for, including disclosures made for the purposes of treatment, payment, health care operations or pursuant to an authorization.  
• Right to Request Restrictions. You have the right to request a restriction or limitation on the use or of your PHI for treatment, payment, or health care operations. We are not required to agree to your request.  
• Right to Request Confidential Communication. You have the right to request that we communicate with you about medical matters in a certain way or at a certain location.  
• Right to a Copy of this Notice. You have the right to a copy of this notice.  
• Complaints. You have the right to file a complaint in writing to us or to the Secretary of Health and Human Services if you believe we have violated your privacy rights. We will not retaliate against you for filing a complaint.  
If you have any questions about this Notice of Privacy Practices, Please contact our Privacy Officer:  
Rick Murphy  
rick@drugrehabcenter.com
